A Finding Aid to the Chaim Gross Papers, 1920-2004, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
- Correspondence, 1926-1997; Series 2; Archival Resource Key; 8.75 Linear feet Boxes 1-9, 22
  - G, General: Gro-Gw, 1935-1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Hadassah, 1964-1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Hadassah, Los Angeles Chapter, 1969-1970; 1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Hadassah Medical Organization, 1965-1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Hadassah, Nassau Region, 1977-1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Hadassah, New York Chapter, 1965-1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Hadassah, Pascack Valley Chapter, 1966-1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Hadassah, Various Chapters and Magazine, 1964-1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Halban, Peter (Mishkenot Sha'ananim Jerusalem), 1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Harmon, Lily, circa 1970-circa 1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Harris, Arthur (Art Harris Gallery), 1971-1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Harriton, Abe and Estelle, 1976-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Harry N. Abrams, Inc., 1965-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Haus der Kunst, Munchen, 1980-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Hebald, Cecille and Milton, circa 1965-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Hebrew Home for the Aged, 1965-1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Hebrew Teachers College, 1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Hebrew Union College-Jewish Institute of Religion, 1971-1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Hebrew University of Jerusalem (Eliyahu Honig), 1964-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Hecht, Reuben R., 1968-1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Heimbach, Sylvia, 1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Henderson, Priscilla, 1967-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Heritage Plantation of Sandwich, 1976-1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Hersey, Irwin and Marcia, circa 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Hertz, Richard C., 1972-1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Hiatt, Frances and Jacob, circa 1965-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - High School of Music and Art, 1941-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Hillcrest Jewish Center, 1969-1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Hirsch, Joe, 1959-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Hise, Albert/The Massilon Museum, 1939-1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 33)
    Detailed letters from Massilon Museum director Albert Hise provide information about the museum's development of their collection of Gross's artwork.
  - Hurwitz (Hurwood), David Lyon, 1968; 1980-1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 34)
    Includes a photograph of Theresa Bernstein and William Meyerowitz in their studio and a photograph of Woldemar Neufeld
  - Hyman, D. Jay, 1964-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Hyman, Irwin H., 1963-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - H, General: H.-Hal, circa 1952-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - H, General: Ham-Hay, 1939-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - H, General: Heb-Hey, 1959-1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - H, General: Hi-Ho, 1939-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - H, General: Hu-Hy, 1942-1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Ilson, Aaron B. and Sylvia, 1967-1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Indiana University, 1941-1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Ingersoll, R. Sturgis, 1960-1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Institute of Contemporary Art, 1951-1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - International Council of Jewish Women (Marilyn Shubin), 1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - International Sculpture Center, 1986-1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - International Synagogue, 1966-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Israel Education Fund, 1966-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Israeli Embassy/Independence Ball, circa 1964-1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Israel Museum, 1965-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - I, General, 1945-1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - Jacobs, Lewis and Lilian, 1940-circa 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - Jesselson, Erica (Shaare Zedek), circa 1979-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - Jewish Community Center, Bayonne, NJ, 1969-1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - Jewish Community Center of Rhode Island, 1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - Jewish Community Center on the Palisades, 1978-1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - Jewish Community Center, Worcester, MA, 1963-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 58)
  - Jewish Currents, 1970-1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 59)
  - Jewish Museum, 1947-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 60)
  - Jewish Museum, 1974-1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 61)
  - Jewish Museum, 1980-1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 62)
  - Jewish Theological Seminary of America, 1947; 1968-1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 63)
  - Jewish Welfare Board, 1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 64)
  - John Jay College of Criminal Justice, Public Art Preservation Committee, 1974-1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 65)
  - John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation, 1936-1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 66)
  - Judaic Heritage Society, 1972-1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 67)
  - J, General: J.-Ja, 1942-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 68)
  - J, General: Je, 1948-1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 69)
    1997 item is an empty envelope
  - J, General: Jo-Ju, 1939-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 70)
  - Kalamazoo Institute of Arts, 1961-1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 71)
  - Kaminsky, David, 1976-1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 72)
  - Kandell, Suki, 1965-1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 73)
  - Kaplan, Ethel and Julius, 1970-1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 74)
  - Kaplan, J. M., 1950-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 75)
  - Karen Horney Clinic, 1958-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 76)
  - Kauvar, Charles and Sara, circa 1969-circa 1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 77)
  - Kessler, Seymour, 1978-1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 78)
  - Klein, Cele and Harris, 1969-1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 79)
  - Kleinberg, Barbara (Bobbie), 1966-1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 80)
  - Kleinman, Seymour, 1974-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 81)
  - Knaths, Karl, 1963-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 82)
    Letters relate to an exchange of artwork between Knaths and Gross.
  - Koehler, John O., circa 1970s-1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Kolleck, Teddy, 1973-1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Kolliner, Beatrice and Melville, circa 1940s-circa 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Kopman, Benjamin, 1937-1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Krasnow, Carrie and Howard, 1980-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Kroll, Leon, 1950-circa 1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - K, General: K.-Kam, 1942-1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - K, General: Kan-Kay, 1942-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - K, General: Ke-Ki, 1942-1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - K, General: Kl, 1946-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - K, General: Kn-Ko, 1939-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - K, General: Kr-Kw, 1936-1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - LaFair, Claude and Isadore, circa 1960s; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - La Jolla Art Center, 1962-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Landau, Norman J., circa 1969-1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Lawrence Gallery/Sidney Lawrence, 1952; 1973-1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Leo N. Levi National Arthritis Hospital, 1973-1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Lerner, Abe, circa 1962-circa 1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Levene, Roslyn, circa 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Licht, Dotty and Frank, 1972-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Limited Arts Limited, 1973-1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - List, Albert A., 1961-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Livingston, Mimi S., 1977-1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Long Beach Friends of Hofstra, 1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Long Island Jewish-Hillside Medical Center, 1971-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Lothrop, Stanley, 1933-1939; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Lubavitch Youth Organization, 1969-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Lyons, Leonard and Sylvia, circa 1967-circa 1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Lyss, Esther and Stanley, circa 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - L, General: L.-La, 1935-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - L, General: Lea-Len, 1944-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - L, General: Leo-Ley, 1929-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - L, General: Li, 1935-1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - L, General: Lo-Lu, 1941-1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - M. H. De Young Memorial Museum, 1948-1949; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - M. Snower & Company, 1953-1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Manhattan IHB League, 1969-1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Manhattanville College, 1968-1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Mann, Sylvia, 1965-1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Marble Arch Gallery, Inc., 1960-1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Maril, Herman, circa 1967-circa 1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Massachusetts College of Art/John Baker, 1978-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Maurice Pine Free Public Library, 1981-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Maza, Gabriel, 1973-1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - McMahon, Audrey, circa 1936-circa 1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - Meilach, Dona Z., 1967-1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - Melford, Maurice A., Sculpture in Replica, 1948-1951; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Menninger Foundation, 1978-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Menorah Home and Hospital for Aged and Infirm, 1964-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - Menorah Journal, 1943-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - Metropolitan Museum of Art, circa 1940-1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - Miami Beach Festival of the Arts, 1979-1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - Michigan State University, 1969-1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - Miller, Marjorie S., circa 1971-1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - Milwaukee Art Center, 1960; 1980-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 55)
  - Miron, Issachar and Tsipora, circa 1970-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 56)
  - Mitchell, Jan, circa 1956-circa 1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 57)
  - Montclair Art Museum, 1945; circa 1976-circa 1980s; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 58)
  - Moskowitz, Charlotte and Lionel, circa 1963-circa 1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 59)
  - Mount Sinai Medical Center, 1976-1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 60)
  - Mowshowitz, Israel, 1967-1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 61)
  - Munson-Williams Proctor Institute, 1941-1943; 1962-1963; 1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 62)
  - Museum of Art of Ogunquit, 1961-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 63)
  - Museum of Modern Art, 1934-1949; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 64)
  - Museum of Modern Art, 1950-1968; 1984-1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 65)
  - Museum of Primitive Art, circa 1959-circa 1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 66)
  - Myerson, Bess, circa 1966-1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 67)
  - M, General: M.-Mao, 1961-1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 68)
  - M, General: Mar-Maz, 1940-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 69)
  - M, General: Mc-Me, 1934-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 70)
  - M, General: Mi, 1957-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 71)
    Includes two letters with a sketch from architect Lester J. Millman who built bases for Gross's sculpture.
  - M, General: Mo-My, 1934-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 72)
    Includes a three-page letter from poet Samuel French Morse.
  - Nassau County Museum of Fine Arts, 1978-1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 73)
  - Nathan, Ann, circa 1971-1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 74)
  - National Academy of Design, 1969-1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - National Association of Women Artists, 1967; 1985-1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - National Broadcasting Company, Inc., 1958-1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - National Council of Jewish Women, 1956-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - National Council on Art in Jewish Life, 1979-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - National Emergency Civil Liberties Committee, 1968-1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - National Gallery of Art, 1969-1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - National Institute of Arts and Letters, 1950-1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - National Multiple Sclerosis Society, 1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - National Tay-Sachs and Allied Diseases Association, 1968-1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Nechin, Sam, circa 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - New School for Social Research, 1948-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - New York Board of Rabbis, 1966-1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - New York Enthusiasts, Inc., 1948-1959; 1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - New York Society for Ethical Culture, Art Auction, 1962-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - New York University, 1940-1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - New York World's Fair (1939), 1938-1939; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Newark Museum, 1940-1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Newman, Arnold and Augusta, 1943-1944; circa 1974-circa 1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Newman, Elias, 1948-1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Nicci, Giovanni and Angelo/Nicci Foundry, 1958-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Norton Gallery and School of Art, 1940-1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Northside Center for Child Development, 1960-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - N, General: N.-Na, 1942-1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - N, General: Nea-New, 1935-1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - N, General: New-Nu, 1942-1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Odes, Richard and Shirley, circa 1964-circa 1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Oestreicher, Gerard, 1959-1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Old Dominion College, 1968-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Oreck, Sandra Zahn, circa 1973-1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Orzac, Bebe and Edward, circa 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - O, General, 1945-1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Packard, Henriette (Henriette Lehman), circa 1964-circa 1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Packard, Henriette (Henriette Lehman), 1964-1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Packard, Henriette (Henriette Lehman), 1975-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Palley, George T., 1950-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Parrish Art Museum, 1981-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Paulson, Rosalind B. (Rosalind B. Stevens), circa 1963-circa 1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Peerce, Alice K. and Jan, circa 1954-circa 1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Pennsylvania Academy of the Fine Arts, 1942-1965; 1984-1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Peso, 1974-1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - Peter M. David Gallery, Inc. (Bonnie Sussman), 1974-1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - Philadelphia Museum of Art, 1942-1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - Philadelphia Museum of Judaica, 1980-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - Philharmonic Symphony of Westchester, Inc., 1965-1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - Phoenix Art Museum, 1969-1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - Piskor, Frank P., 1966-1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - Pollack, Jerry and Marcia, 1963-1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - Poses, Jack and Lillian, circa 1974-circa 1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 49)
  - Posner, Judith, 1978-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 50)
  - Potok, Chaim, 1969-1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 51)
  - Press, Freda, 1972-1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 52)
  - Primoff & Primoff, 1963-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 53)
  - Propp, Enia Alter, 1976-1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 54)
  - Provincetown Art Association, 1939; 1959-1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 55)
  - P, General: P.-Pa, 1939-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 56)
  - P, General: Pe-Ph, 1947-1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 57)
  - P, General: Pi-Pl, 1944-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 58)
  - P, General: Po-Py, 1948-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 59)
  - Queens College, 1938-1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 60)
  - Q, General, circa 1960s; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 61)
  - Rabinowitz, Stanley, 1972-1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 62)
  - Reform Congregation Keneseth Israel, 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 63)
  - Reiss-Davis Clinic for Child Guidance, 1960-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 64)
  - Rhode Island School of Design, 1964-1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 65)
  - Rich, Jack C., 1946-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 66)
  - Richmond, Howard S., circa 1971-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 67)
  - Richmond, Lawrence, 1956-1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 68)
  - Robbins, Anita and Norman B., circa 1967-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 69)
  - Robbins, Warren/Museum of African Art, circa 1963-circa 1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 70)
  - Robbins, Warren/Museum of African Art, 1963-1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 71)
  - Robbins, Warren/Museum of African Art, 1976-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 72)
  - Robinson, Edward G. and Jane, circa 1964-1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 73)
  - Robinson Galleries, Inc., 1939-1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 74)
  - Rosen, Saul, 1949-1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 75)
  - Royal Society of Arts, 1968-1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 76)
  - Ruder & Finn Incorporated, 1964-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 77)
  - Rutgers University, 1961-1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 78)
  - Ruttenberg, Harold J. and Kitty, 1967-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Ruttenberg, Harold J. and Kitty, 1971-1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Ruttenberg, Harold J. and Kitty, 1976-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - R, General: R.-Red, 1941-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - R, General: Ree-Ri, 1938-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - R, General: Rob-Rose, 1941-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - R, General: Rosen-Rossmore, 1946-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 7)
    Includes four cards and notes from May Tabak Rosenberg with original drawings by Patia Rosenberg.
  - R, General: Rost-Ry, 1935-1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Saint John, Robert and Ruth, circa 1970s-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Saint Paul Art Center, 1963-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Salinas, Marcel, 1968-1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Samour, Fimi, 1972-1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Sandman, Edna, circa 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Sapinsley, Milton C., circa 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Saypol, Grace/Sisterhood of Temple Israel, 1970-1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Schaeffer, Freda and Harry, circa 1960s-circa 1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Schimmel, Michael, 1965-1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Schneider, Ruth R., 1974-1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Scholastic Awards/Scholastic Magazines, Inc., 1951-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Sculptors Guild Inc., circa 1956-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Seawright, Sandy (Nashville Banner), 1976-1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Sex Information and Education Council of the U. S. (SIECUS), 1970-1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Shaifer, Norman (Custom Color Communications), 1972-1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Shapiro, Sadie, 1965-1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Shinkle, Jackson L., 1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Shore Studio Galleries, 1955-1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Simon, Bernard, 1964-1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Singer, Alma and Isaac Bashevis, circa 1971-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Sklar, Albert L., 1973-1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Sklaroff, Robert and Family, circa 1970s-circa 1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Skowhegan School of Painting and Sculpture, circa 1947-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Slosberg, Helen S., circa 1962-circa 1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Smithsonian Institution, 1968-1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Smithsonian Institution, American Art Museum, 1958-1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Smithsonian Institution, American Art Museum, 1975-1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - Smithsonian Institution, Hirshhorn Museum and Sculpture Garden, 1967-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - Snow, John C., 1961-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - Solomon, Joseph, 1972-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - Solomon R. Guggenheim Museum, 1956-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - Sosland, Louis and Rheta, 1963-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - Soyer, Moses, circa 1960s-1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - Soyer, Raphael and Family, circa 1970s-1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - Sperakis, Nick, 1970-1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 43)
  - Spiegel, Barbara and Edward, circa 1966-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 44)
  - Spoleto Festival, 1974-1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 45)